UTKARSH SINGH

USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

ABOUT ME

Hello! My 2+ years of experience in UX design and 6+ years in the design industry make me a seasoned design-stronaut. I used to design physical experiences as an Architect, but I found my true calling in the digital galaxy. My diverse background has allowed me to approach UX design with a holistic perspective to create truly delightful experiences.

EXPERIENCE

UX Specialist - Project Assistant // VARLab

WATERLOO, CANADA • FEB 2023 - PRESENT

I help design various digital learning simulations for industry application at VARLab - Virtual and Augmented Reality Lab.

Co-Founder & UX Designer // Deziko

MOHALI, INDIA . AUG 2021 - PRESENT

Deziko Web LLP is a startup specializing in design competitions. It owns and operates two websites - the Charette.org and Deziko.co.

Responsibilities:

- Led UX/UI design and Web Development
- Marketing & Social Media Strategy
- Business Strategy

Achievements:

- Achieved profitability within 6 months of launching the business.
- Increased website traffic to ~4,000 monthly users (MAU).
- Created a social media strategy that resulted in ~25,000 followers.

Architectural Designer // The Architects Collaborative MOHALI, INDIA • AUG 2017 – JUL 2021 (4 YRS)

Led end-to-end design process of various architectural projects. Most of my work was a collaborative effort with many stakeholders involved in the design and construction process. My responsibilities were:

- Empathize with people, define their needs and desires.
- Make digital prototypes.
- Iterate on designs based on feedback.
- Hand-off the designs to the engineering team for implementation.

Design Intern // Bruno Rollet Architecte

PARIS, FRANCE • SEP 2015 - DEC 2015 (4 MOS)

Designed digital 3D models and physical design models, and construction drawings for residential buildings in France.

CONTACT

www.utkarsh-singh.com

in linkedin.com/in/utkarshello

L +1 (437) 366-8170

EDUCATION

Conestoga College

Interactive Media Management -Interaction Design

Kitchener, Canada • JAN 2023 - AUG 2023 (1 YR)

Panjab University

Bachelor of Architecture, Design 70% Marks (First Division)

Chandigarh, India • AUG 2012 – JUN 2017 (5 YRS)

AWARDS

National Sketching Competition

FIRST PRIZE • 2009 Organized by Hyundai

Website Design Competition

FIRST PRIZE • 2009
Organized by Hindustan Times

Governor's House Re-design

FIRST PRIZE • 2017
Awarded by the Governor of Punjab

Poster Design Competition

SECOND PRIZE • 2014
Concrete Action 2014 Conference

TOOLS

Design:

Figma, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Illustrator, Miro, FigJam, iPad

Web:

Wordpress, Basic HTML & CSS

3D modeling:

Sketchup, Rhino 3D, V-Ray